I had never even dreamed
of the sight I saw that day.
Even now, after so, so long,
my memory of it hasn't faded in the slightest.
But how I've longed to see him,
even if it were only in a dream...
I miss him.
I want to see him one more time...
Am I...
All right?
Yes.
More importantly, is Ms. Murasame...
No, is Phantom nearby?
She's nowhere in the vicinity.
It would seem she's disappeared.
That was too easy.
Though a Spirit that's divided its power
too greatly wouldn't amount to much more.
However, defeating Phantom doesn't
mean I've achieved my goal.
Yes, yes. Of course not.
Our goal isn't the present fragmented fool.
It's the monster of the past
at its full power.
Still, why would Phantom divide
her power to create more Spirits?
She must have known that would
inevitably spell her own decline.
So you're saying Kurumi
has saved you over 204 times?
Yeah.
Every time I got killed,
she rewound time and stopped DEM's attack.
Kurumi's goal is to go back in time
and defeat the Spirit of Origin
in order to save her best friend.
She also means to prevent all tragedy
caused by Spirits before it ever happens.
And she needs my Spirit power to do that.
I can't believe that's what was
going on with Kurumi...
I'm surprised.
So even the Sephirah within each of us
were refined at the cost of
countless human lives...
I have mixed feelings about that.
Whatever Kurumi's reasons may be,
we can't afford to hand over
Shido's Spirit power.
That comes above all else.
For one thing,
we don't have any guarantee that Kurumi
can even defeat this Spirit of Origin.
Her story's also hard for me to believe.
That's right. You've fought Kurumi
plenty of times already.
But—
Even so!
If you ask me if it's more likely
that you're lying to me, big brother,
then I'm forced to believe you two
by a narrow margin.
This is getting complicated.
Though I understand what you're getting at.
More importantly, big brother,
there's one other thing
I'm very concerned about.
Hmm?
This Mio Takamiya woman
that came up in your story.
I find it hard to believe
she's unrelated to you and me.
If her last name really is Takamiya,
then there's a chance she's family.
A blood relative.
I was curious about that too.
Who is this Mio Takamiya?
And what is she creating Spirits for?
She gave Kurumi her Sephirah
and made her a Spirit.
Sounds like the Phantom
that appeared before us.
Mio Takamiya...
Phantom...
And the Spirit of Origin
that Kurumi mentioned...
Question.
What is the relationship between all three?
If only we could use my Raziel...
Then we'd have our answer in an instant.
Indeed, it's a peculiar story, but...
If you're so curious,
all you have to do is
remember your past, right?
If only I could.
But both Mana and I have lost
our memories.
We don't even know a single
thing about why we lost them.
You told me that before.
That's why I'm saying
you should try remembering.
You think I can?
My Michael is an absolute key.
There's nothing it can't open.
Not even the door to your sealed memories.
Hold on!
Is it safe to do something like that?
I don't know what happened in the past,
but it won't harm Darling
the moment he remembers, will it?
Big brother...
I'll be all right.
Don't worry.
This isn't just about
our connection to Mio Takamiya.
I want to know what happened in our past
more than anyone else.
Shido...
Michael!
Okay, here I go.
Yeah!
Don't worry.
Believe in Michael.
Such a long, hard object is going into Darling!
Miku, be quiet for a bit.
No! You can't! Don't!
Oh, you've awakened, Shin.
Wha?!
Hmm? Is something wrong?
Oh, no, it's nothing.
Shido!
Are you okay?
Please take it easy.
What's this now?
What's going on?
What do you mean, "What's going on"?!
You suddenly collapsed and gave us a fright!
Agreed.
After inserting Michael into your head,
you passed out.
Huh?
I see. Sorry.
Guess I worried you all.
No, what matters is you woke up.
I knew my kiss would work.
It woke Sleeping Beauty.
Huh?
What nonsense are you spouting now?
Don't listen to her, Shido.
Wait a minute now.
There are numerous particles
floating in this space,
so you can't say for certain that ones
from my breath didn't reach Shido's.
So I see no problem with regarding
this as an indirect kiss.
Hold it right there, Professor!
That would mean that me and everyone
in this same room have been...
Deeply entwined in a deep kiss.
I can't believe such genius lies here!
What has the scientific world
been doing this whole time?!
Hold on. I'm not following now.
Just how are we all entwined?
I'll explain it in practice later!
While Natsumi joins us for a three-way!
Could you not rope me into this too?
I'm sorry, Master.
This was all because
I suggested using Michael.
Oh, no. Nothing's actually wrong.
See? I'm just fine!
Master...
So, big brother,
what happened?
Did you remember anything?
Well, I...
Huh? That's odd.
I'm certain I saw something.
Yet I can't remember anything.
There's no need to hurry, Shin.
You can just think of another way.
Reine...
Then could you try it on me too, big brother?
Huh?
It might not have worked for you,
but I might be able to remember something.
Whether it's about Mio Takamiya
or whatever happened to us in the past.
Yeah, yeah.
We'll try that later, okay?
Right now, let's wait
for Shido to recover first.
Huh?
What's the big idea?
She's right.
I'm sorry, Mana.
Can we try it another time?
Hmm?
Ike, you said you found something?
How has Nightmare, Kurumi Tokisaki,
been able to interfere
with every one of our attacks?
She's been aware of our plans in advance.
To be precise,
she's actually experienced them,
then altered things each time
to avoid Shido Itsuka's death.
What?
That would spell trouble.
It means we'll always be a step behind.
Indeed.
Though we're not necessarily
at a disadvantage.
Any strategy we conduct several times,
Nightmare will have to face
several hundred times.
Repeating the same thing
over and over will exhaust her mind.
Even Nightmare can't have
endless stamina and willpower.
Are you suggesting we wait
until Nightmare gives up?
That's our most certain option.
However, there's still a chance
Nightmare could come up with
some solution we won't be able to think of.
So we should also do everything in our power
to ensure she gives up as soon as possible.
Father, Father!
Look, look!
We caught this.
Nightmare!
Eavesdropping, huh?
Well done, Nibeelcole.
But several people she was with got away.
They might have overheard your conversation.
What's wrong with that?
Let's have an all-out war with full knowledge
of each other's capabilities.
There's still at least one of you left, right?
Tell your master for me...
I will kill Itsuka Shido.
No matter how many times you go back in time.
No matter how often you redo this world
or how often you rewrite history.
I'll be so thorough that
there's no overturning it.
Now, struggle all you like,
vilest Spirit.
I was relieved Mana
backed down for us yesterday.
She had her magic power
enhanced by DEM, after all.
If she'd recalled those memories too,
it would have been pretty damaging.
Even if we want intel on Mio Takamiya.
Mio Takamiya, huh?
I wonder why...
I feel sure I've known
that name for a long time now.
Kurumi!
Good day, Shido, Kotori.
Good morning, Kurumi.
You're wearing an awfully
nice outfit today, aren't you?
It's her clone.
Thank you for last night.
I should thank you.
But it's still too early for you
to be thanking me.
Huh?
On February 20th, DEM Industries
will use their full forces
to come kill you, Shido.
I came here today to warn you of that.
So, what's your objective?
To be honest,
the main body of Kurumi Tokisaki doesn't
know that I, her clone, am here right now.
The real me intends to handle
this matter all on our own.
She plans to repeat time as often as it takes
to seize a future in which Shido survives.
However, our enemy is aware of her resolve.
That's why they're using their full forces.
DEM's operation
is also an attempt to break my spirit
as I pass through time.
So the real reason you're here is
to encourage Shido to evacuate?
That alone is not the entirety of the truth.
Huh?
It would be a waste for Shido
to remain in the dark
when I'm working so hard
to protect him, wouldn't it?
I get it.
Now, if you'll excuse me.
Please do survive this, Shido.
Kurumi!
Yes, what is it?
If it's possible, tell Kurumi:
"Thank you. I'm still alive because of you.
But I won't be the one
in need of saving forever.
Once we've taken care of DEM,
I'll come to seal your Spirit power—"
No, that's not right.
"This time, I'll be the one to steal a kiss.
So prepare yourself, my honey."
What a wonderful retort.
I'm truly blessed.
Wednesday, February 15th
You have a new message.
Kotori
Today
Reine, come to the meeting room
We have an emergency.
You're coming, Wizard?
The situation is dire.
Judging from the state of things,
the information we received from
Kurumi's clone is worth believing.
Though we also can't afford
to run and hide forever.
But there's no negotiating either.
Certainly.
There's no room for discussion here.
Which means...
We only have one option left.
Defeating DEM.
Of course, that's easier said than done.
But we'll have to go on the offensive
in order to seize our own future.
That's right, Commander Itsuka.
Mr. Woodman!
Are you feeling better already?
Yes, you don't need to worry about me.
I'm sorry I was out of contact for so long.
Our enemy is certainly great.
However, DEM is an organization helmed
by Isaac Westcott's charisma
and Ellen Mathers's competence.
That means it won't be much of a threat
once those two are taken out.
In other words, defeating Westcott
and Ellen is our key to victory.
Understood.
Then perhaps it would be worth trying that.
Huh?
MARIA, what do you mean by "that"?
I'm saying that it might be
possible to nullify Nibeelcole.
Huh?!
Truthfully, I also have an idea
for how to handle Bandersnatch.
H-Hold on!
The enemy's new Realizer models are—
Stop, stop!
Enough talking about it.
What's the matter, Nia?
We're just getting to the main topic.
Tsk, tsk, tsk.
You don't get it, Robo-girl.
First, I demand an explanation
for that nickname.
Depending on your answer,
I may eject you from the ship.
Have you forgotten?
Westcott can use Beelzebub,
the omniscient Demon King.
Ah!
That's right.
He can look up any event that happens
throughout the entire universe.
Meaning...
He might learn everything
that unfolds in this discussion.
Exactly.
However,
it doesn't know how to read people's minds
or what the future holds.
So even if you come up with a strategy,
you can't mention it out loud.
I hate to admit it, but you are correct.
Thank you, Nia.
As long as you understand!
Humility is a virtue,
spriteless Robo-girl.
By the way, Nia, could you
please touch my console?
Huh? Like this?
Hey! What are you doing?! Come on!
I'm grateful for the flaw you pointed out.
However, you needed to be punished
for that insulting nickname.
That's false logic!
Still, it's rather absurd that we have to have
our strategy meeting without being
able to voice any ideas or opinions.
I think there are still things
we can each do on our own.
There's something I'd like to take care of, too.
Good point.
I'll do everything I can as well.
Do you have any excuse for yourself?
My, oh my.
I already received word from another me.
I heard you informed Shido
and Kotori about DEM's assault.
I can't have you acting on your own
without orders from me.
You'll need to pay for disturbing
the order with your life.
Yes, yes. There's no getting past that.
But one last thing.
I have a message from Shido.
"I love, love, super-love you!
Let's get married, my honey!"
Only the "my honey" part of that was accurate!
I know you already heard it
from another clone.
My, oh my.
I wouldn't be so foolish
as to pare down my own forces
right before a major battle.
If you are still a part of me,
then at least be useful first
and then die on the battlefield for me.
Yes, yes. I understand.
A secret organization protecting Spirits, huh?
You show up out of nowhere,
and you expect us to believe that nonsense?
B-But Captain,
they've both come here
knowing it meant great danger.
I don't think we should be
so quick to assume they're lying.
I know you must find it hard to believe.
But it's all true.
On February 20th,
there will likely be a major
battle here in Tengu City.
When it goes down,
DEM will probably request
even the captains sortie.
But I want you to ignore that request.
Is that also information uncovered
by the secret organization Ratatoskr?
Still, even if what you say is true...
That's right.
Spurning DEM's request means
ignoring orders from above.
So you're asking us to lose our jobs
and serve prison time on top of that?
For one thing,
why are you telling us
not to attack the Spirits?
They're the enemy of mankind, aren't they?
That's maliciously spun
information spread by DEM.
The Spirits have no intention
of attacking mankind.
That's a lot to take in all at once.
If what you just told us is true,
then I would love to try fiddling with this
secret organization's new weapons!
It's stirring my instincts as a mechanic!
Sorry, but could you be quiet for a bit?
You know we can't do what you're asking.
Captain...
That's a shame.
Though I don't fault you for your decision.
Still, if you do deploy to the battlefield,
at least stick to the rear.
Huh?
I don't want to kill you all.
Sounds like you're really
underestimating us.
I know you were a skilled fighter, but...
Please.
Zaphkiel, Het!
Het!
Het, Het, Het, Het, Het, Het,
Now, shall we begin our Date?
Episode 1
Beginnings of War
Episode 2   "Final Respite"
The big battle against DEM draws near,
with everyone harboring different feelings
as they spend what time remains.
Next time is episode 2, "Final Respite."
The curtain rises on Date A Live season 5!